Oliver Geoffrey Shepherd

The Courtyard, The Green, Chiddingfold, Surrey, GU8 4TU

Phone: 07498 581894

Email: ogshepherd@gmail.com

Experienced **software start-up leader**, having a successful track record of bringing products to market, developing and growing high-performing teams and implementing supporting systems. Track record of success in start-up and turnaround in technology and property sectors, having specialized in **creating customer-focused solutions and building scalable systems**.

An inquisitive business leader with a collegiate approach. **9+ years senior management experience**. Credited with **combining Operational**, **Strategic and Financial expertise with strong interpersonal skills** in start-ups to PLCs. Significant experience of people, process management and systems implementation.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Supporting CEOs and Key Stakeholders to Design and Deliver Strategy

- Developed, communicated and implemented the strategic plan for CSR Connect.
- Devised international B2B and B2C strategies for ITEMS for Health.
- Managed and co-ordinated best-in-class operational team across central functions including replacing and retaining outgoing General Manager at Star BMS.

Delivering Client-Focussed Products and Services

- Led the redesign of the software at CSR Connect in line with feedback from market research
- Supported CEO of ITEMS for Health in rebuild of software based on feedback from pilot schemes and further market research.
- Returned Star BMS to profitability within 12 months through rebuilding client relationships and improving service standards.

Ensuring Successful Delivery of Operational Excellence

- Developed and oversaw best practise processes and systems across core functions at CSR Connect.
- Implemented operational platforms and processes to refocus a disconnected and regionally dispersed team at Star BMS.
- Developed efficient and effective delivery and on-boarding processes for ITEMS for Health, a SaaS software programme, to maximise user engagement.

Implementing Digital Transformation Projects for Organisational Change

- Developed tailored ERP systems for CSR Connect and ITEMS for Health to incorporate CRM, Intranet, Marketing and Project Management.
- Managed the customisation, implementation and change management process for the successful takeup of a new CRM system for Australia's second largest body corporate manager.
- Led the development and implementation of an in-house CRM system for SEGRO Plc.

KEY INFORMATION

Used to operating from fully equipped home office, London offices, or any South East location as required. Many years' experience of managing and motivating geographically spread, remote teams. Experience across technology, sustainability, healthcare and property industries.

In April 2020, CSR Connect was closed at the point of launch due to the Lockdown. Recently active with Women in Banking and Finance (WIBF) as a Thought Leadership Team Volunteer, to assist in obtaining sponsorship for their Accelerating Change Together research programme.

CAREER HISTORY

COO, CSR Connect (t/a Etoso) (London)

2019 - April 2020

A sustainability reporting SaaS system. Responsibility for strategic planning and execution, and all operational activity with a primary investor holding CEO title.

- Full P&L, Budget and business plan responsibility, including development of go-to-market strategy.
- Redesigned and redeveloped software and branding in line with feedback from market research.
- Employed new operations and sales teams and engaged them in pre-launch activities.
- Engaged new remote development team and managed on time and on budget delivery of software.
- Devised and developed operational systems, processes and procedures to support growth and client management

CO-FOUNDER & COO, ITEMS for Health (Brisbane & London)

2013 - 2019

A talent management SaaS system provider with clients in Australia, Canada and the UK. Supporting the CEO in strategic planning and execution, responsible for all operational activity.

- Full P&L, Budget and business plan responsibility, including marketing strategy.
- Devised and developed operational systems, processes and procedures to support growth and client management leading to 90%+ client retention.
- Managing key stakeholders, including investors, banks and partners to secure investment, finance and scale more rapidly.
- Recruiting and training sales, marketing and administrative staff both in-house and outsourced.
- Successfully raised seed funding in excess of AUD\$250,000.

GENERAL MANAGER, Star BMS (Brisbane)

2010 - 2013

A property asset management company serving Queensland and New South Wales, Australia. Acting with MD responsibilities, successfully performed a turnaround from loss-making to profitability.

- Developed strategy for recovery and growth, increasing revenue by 50% within 12 months and implementing major cost savings.
- Doubled the team and engaged agents across multiple sites to develop business.
- Developed systems and processes to address low engagement and business performance.
- Implemented tailored CRM system to improve efficiency and sales performance.
- Board presence at 93-strong parent company with \$20m per annum turnover.

ASSET MANAGER, Derwent London Plc (London)

2007-2010

Derwent London is a FTSE100 company and the leading Central London Office REIT. Responsible for the asset management of a 1.4 million sq ft property portfolio with a £33m annual revenue.

- Proposed and implementing strategic asset management initiatives to maximise value, increasing rent roll from £29m to £33m from 2007 to 2010.
- Assisting in the creation of the Fitzrovia Partnership to represent the interests of a group of key stakeholders, residents and the Borough Council.
- Key account management: Established and maintained tenant relations to maximise tenant retention and expansion. Completed a new lease at a rent of £960,000 pa.
- Managing multi-disciplinary teams to ensure best service to tenants.

• Implementing and managing a Tenants at Risk schedule, a monitor of tenants either in financial difficulty or with the potential to be in financial difficulty.

LEASING SURVEYOR, SEGRO Pic (Slough)

2005 - 2007

A FTSE100 company and one of Europe's largest providers of business space. Led the letting of speculative developments on the Slough Trading Estate.

- Developed a new in-house CRM software system. The system acted as a management tool for the leasing process, a reporting system with various facets and applications.
- Let industrial and office space on the Slough Trading Estate including a new 2,322 sq m industrial warehouse prior to commencement of marketing.
- Advised Asset Management, Development & Refurbishment colleagues in relation to market requirements.
- Reported on Lost Business from Slough Trading Estate, developed the company's approach to customer management.
- Prepared 5-year leasing budget for the Slough Trading Estate and directly reported on analysis of vacant standing stock.

COMMERCIAL MANAGER, Dreweatt Neate (Andover)

2003 - 2005

A domestic and commercial property agency with offices across the South of England.

- Assisted with and subsequently ran the commercial agency business for Dreweatt Neate in Andover, acting in the letting and sales of office and industrial premises over 67 properties with 33 clients.
- Completed the largest office letting in town for ten years.
- Set the record rent per square foot for industrial space.

GRADUATE SURVEYOR, Colliers CRE, (London)

2000 - 2003

Colliers CRE is a leading international property consultancy.

 Gained experience of commercial property valuations, out of town retail agency, rent reviews and business rates, worked with clients including Alliance & Leicester, Lloyds TSB, Diageo.

QUALIFICATIONS

Business Coaching Certificate, CTC (Distinction)	2016 - 2017
Scalable & Saleable Entrepreneurship Programme, Sydney	2012 - 2013
Member of the Royal Institution of Chartered Surveyors (MRICS), lapsed 2011	2000 - 2002
BSc (Hons) – Valuation and Estate Management, UWE, Bristol	1995 - 1999

INTERESTS

Software programming (Python, React.js and now entering machine learning and AI), reading (business, personal development and novels), mountain biking, tennis, skiing and watching rugby.

REFERENCES

References are available on request.